<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on A minimal Hugo website</title>
    <link>https://example.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on A minimal Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Final Election Prediction</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/2024/10/30/final-election-prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/2024/10/30/final-election-prediction/</guid>
      <description>Overview Election week has come! It is a very scary time. We are all biting our nails in anticipation of the result on Tuesday and, of course, in anticipation of the predictions from the Election Analytics class. This entire semester, I have been developing a three-stage model that predicts the election results, and I am excited to provide a brief overview of my methodology, as well as my final predictions and simulations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog Post 8: Final Touch Ups</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/2024/10/26/blog-post-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/2024/10/26/blog-post-8/</guid>
      <description>Unfortunately, for this blog, I am largely out of material. This week I have made several touch ups to the raw data files — I noticed that some population totals were incorrect, as well as some of the voting results in Maine’s two districts and Nebraska’s three districts. I also replaced the 2024 CPR forecast with their most up-to-date electoral college predictions. Neither of these updates strongly affected my predictions either at the state level or the national level.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog Post 7: More Simulation</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/2024/10/16/blog-post-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/2024/10/16/blog-post-7/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Simulation has become the bane of my existence. Two weeks ago, I implemented a simple simulation approach, in which I set the predicted value for each state to be the mean of a normal random variable with a standard deviation of 3 percent. Of course, the 3 percent number was entirely arbitrary, so last week, I tried a more complicated approach, where I introduced uncertainty in my estimates &amp;mdash; the vector of coefficients \(\vec{\beta}\) &amp;mdash; rather than the predictions themselves.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog Post 6: Simulation</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/2024/10/12/blog-post-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/2024/10/12/blog-post-6/</guid>
      <description>Overview Okay, something is seriously wrong with my model. Recall that my final model’s predictions involve an ensemble between the fundamentals model and the polling model. Well, this week when I ran the model, I realized that the ensemble assigned a negative weight to the fundamentals model. Admittedly it was only slightly negative, but still — that shouldn’t happen. Immediately, alarm bells went off. First of all, I modified the ensemble model from performing ordinary least squares, your classic regression, to non-negative least squares, which imposes an added restriction that all coefficients must be non-negative.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog Post 5: Quantifying Uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/2024/10/06/blog-post-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/2024/10/06/blog-post-5/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I finally completed the full extent of my model architecture! We have now incorporated most of the data that we will use in our final model, multiple layers of prediction using an elastic net regression with optimized parameters, and model ensembling. Three items are on our agenda for this week. First, I will fix a few lingering errors that I noticed in last week’s model. Then, I will build a visualization for my 2024 election predictions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog Post 4: Model Improvements</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/2024/09/25/blog-post-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/2024/09/25/blog-post-4/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week, I plan to take a step back and fully refine and optimize my model that I have created over the past few weeks. I will only include a single new source of already clean data &amp;mdash; the Cook Political Report expert ratings &amp;mdash; which means that I plan to devote the full post to code and methodological improvements.&#xA;As a reminder, my current model proceeds in three steps.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog Post 3: Polling</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/2024/09/18/blog-post-3-polling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/2024/09/18/blog-post-3-polling/</guid>
      <description>Overview Last week, I developed a comprehensive structure that can be used to build a model that combines the fundamentals with a current snapshot of the political climate in order to forecast the electoral college. The model proceeded in three steps:&#xA;Forecast each state&amp;rsquo;s elasticity, which represents the change in state-level vote margin between two election cycles. This metric measures the &amp;ldquo;swinginess&amp;rdquo; of a state. Forecast each state&amp;rsquo;s partisan lean, which measures the extent to which a state is either more democratic or more republican than the national popular vote.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog Post 2: Economic Fundamentals</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/2024/09/11/blog-post-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/2024/09/11/blog-post-2/</guid>
      <description>Overview This week, I will expand the predictive model for the 2024 presidential election that I developed last week. In my previous model, I used the &amp;ldquo;partisan lean index&amp;rdquo; (PLI) &amp;mdash; which measures the difference between the state&amp;rsquo;s democratic two-party vote share and the two party democratic vote share nationwide, and includes adjustments for home state advantage and state-level population density &amp;mdash; in the previous two election cycles to predict the electoral college results for the current election cycle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog Post 1: Historical Election Data</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/2024/09/05/blog-post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/2024/09/05/blog-post-1/</guid>
      <description>In this first blog post, I will analyze and visualize historical presidential election data in order to better understand trends in the electoral college and develop a naive predictive model for the 2024 election. I will complete extension 1 as some exploratory analysis of my own.&#xA;Electoral College Timeline Below I have produced two electoral college maps for the previous presidential elections from 1948 to 2020. The following interactive map plots the electoral college results for each election at the state level:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Hugo XMin</title>
      <link>https://example.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/about/</guid>
      <description>XMin is the first Hugo theme I have designed. The original reason that I wrote it was I needed a minimal example of Hugo themes when I was writing the blogdown book. Basically I wanted a simple theme that supports a navigation menu, a home page, other single pages, lists of pages, blog posts, categories, tags, and RSS. That is all. Nothing fancy. In terms of CSS and JavaScript, I really want to keep them minimal.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
