<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on A minimal Hugo website</title>
    <link>https://example.org/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on A minimal Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.org/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Blog Post 2: Economic Fundamentals</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/2024/09/11/blog-post-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/2024/09/11/blog-post-2/</guid>
      <description>This week, I will expand the predictive model for the 2024 presidential election that I developed last week. In my previous model, I used the &amp;ldquo;partisan lean index&amp;rdquo; (PLI) &amp;mdash; which measures the difference between the state&amp;rsquo;s democratic two-party vote share and the two party democratic vote share nationwide, and includes adjustments for home state advantage and state-level population density &amp;mdash; in the previous two election cycles to predict the electoral college results for the current election cycle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog Post 1: Historical Election Data</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/2024/09/05/blog-post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/2024/09/05/blog-post-1/</guid>
      <description>In this first blog post, I will analyze and visualize historical presidential election data in order to better understand trends in the electoral college and develop a naive predictive model for the 2024 election. I will complete extension 1 as some exploratory analysis of my own.&#xA;Electoral College Timeline Below I have produced two electoral college maps for the previous presidential elections from 1948 to 2020. The following interactive map plots the electoral college results for each election at the state level:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
